A Guide to the Papers of George Green Shackelford and the Shackelford Family, 1909-1990
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of George Green Shackelford and the Shackelford Family 1909-1990
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3525-as, -at
This collection consists of ca. 2500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The items were gifts on 1990 July 30 and August 30.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists chiefly of correspondence between Shackelford and his brothers Lyne Moncure Shackelford and Virginius Randolph Shackelford, his wife Grace Howard McConnell Shackelford, his father Virginius Randolph Shackelford, and several nieces and nephews.
Topics include Lyne and Shackelford family genealogy, family financial and business matters, family property including "Willow Grove," the Monticello Association, and the University of Virginia, particularly the Alumni Association, the West Lawn Marching and Chowder Society, and the 1941 football team and its five year reunions.
Of interest are letters, 1982-83, describing trips to Egypt and sub-Sahara Africa, a letter from Fiske Kimball dating "Willow Grove," a photo album, ca. 1850, belonging to Mrs. Belle Kirk Shackelford, and a biography of George Scott Shackelford.
Contents List
- Lyne Family Genealogy 1909, 1944-1990 (Box 1)
  3525-as
- "George Scott Shackelford" 1985 (Box 1)
- Grace Howard (McConnell) Shackelford 1925-1989 (Box 1)
- Lyne Moncure Shackelford 1948-1989, 3 folders (Box 1)
- Peachy Lyne Shackelford Estate 1973-1984 (Box 2)
- Virginius Randolph Shackelford and Jr. 1943-1990, n.d., 3 folders (Box 2)
- Virginius Randolph Shackelford, Jr. 1956-1983 (Box 2)
- Shackelford Brothers 1976-1990 (Box 3)
- Shackelford Family Genealogy 1953-1986 (Box 3)
- Willow Grove 1951-1983 (Box 3)
- University of Virginia Alumni Activities 1956-1975 (Box 3)
- University of Virginia Chowders: West Lawn Marching and Chowder Society 1962-1983 (Box 3)
- University of Virginia Football Team Reunion 1941 1941-1942, 1971-1986 (Box 3)
- University of Virginia Library 1955-1989 (Box 4)
- Miniature Photograph Album belonging to Mrs. Belle Kirk Shackelford ca. 1850 (Box 4)
  3525-at
- Passports of George Green and Grace Howard (McConnell) Shackelford 1953-1987 (Box 4)